# NATHANAEL WHITE

Waco, TX

**Phone:** (254)405-4908 | **Email:** nathanaeltwhite@gmail.com **LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/nathanael-white-19726b205/ | **GitHub:** https://github.com/NathanaelWhite | **Portfolio:** 

https://nathanaelwhite.github.io/Nathanael-White-portfolio/

#### SUMMARY

Knowledgeable Web Developer with advanced coding abilities and enthusiasm for new enhancements. Expert in building high-performing, scalable well structures for today and future client needs. Advanced in Sequelize and JavaScript programming languages. Collaborative and productive with excellent problem-solving and communication abilities.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, CSS, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL,

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, NoSQL,

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap, Jest

#### **PROJECTS**

### Jot It |

### github.com/NathanaelWhite/Jot-It | jotitgood.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: A note taking website for anyone working on a project with the option to edit, save, and delete notes.
- Role: Front-end UI and functionality, Back-end routes and database
- Tools: Sequelize, ExpressJS, MySQL2, Handlebars, Bootstrap, Javascript, ESLint

#### NBA Alley Oop |

## github.com/NathanaelWhite/NBA-Alley-Oop | sadractijerina.github.io/NBA-Alley-Oop/

- Summary: An application for users to learn about NBA teams. The user can choose a specific team and then be taken to a page with information about the team selected.
- Role: API integration and functionality
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Materialize

#### **Book Search Engine** |

## github.com/NathanaelWhite/Book-Search-Engine

- pacific-everglades-48895.herokuapp.com/
  - Summary: An application that allows users to to search for their favorite books and add them to a 'favorites' list for later use.
  - Role: Sole author
  - Tools: MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, GraphQL, Bootstrap

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Strength and Conditioning Coach Integrity Strength & Conditioning**

2019 - Current Waco,TX

Planned, organized and conducted training and conditioning programs. *Key Accomplishments:* 

 Maximized individual performance with effective varied workouts to optimize strength, speed, and endurance.

# Synergy Release Practitioner Self-employed

2019 - 2021 Waco,TX

Provider of Synergy Release Method therapeutic services, balancing skeletal and muscular

systems through stretches and release techniques to maximize healing. Certified Pastoral Medical Association and member of Professional Wellness Alliance.

Head Men's Gymnastics Coach Zero Gravity Gymnastics Academy 2018 - 2019

Robinson,TX

Organized practices and lead team workouts. Incorporated team building exercises for individual growth and team development.

Assistant CrossFit Trainer CrossFit Waco

2015 - 2019

Waco,TX

Assisted coaching for group workouts and organized individual plans for athletes' success

**EDUCATION** 

**Certificate, Full Stack Web Development** – University of Texas

Austin ,TX

Certification, CFL1 -- Crossfit Inc.

Tulsa, OK

**Certificate, Synergy Release Method** -- SRM

Waco,TX

Credits toward general degree program -- Mclennan Community College

Waco,TX